A Guide to the O. Henry Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6333-g
O. Henry Collection
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6333-g
1 item
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift 29 Oct 1973
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - " Strictly Business " by O. Henry, ca. 1908; AMsS, 48 p.
    [Includes article as printed in
    Broadway Magazine
    , 8 p. with illustrations by Alexander Popini. ] (Bound in burgundy leather)
  - " Thimble, Thimble [Thumble] " by O. Henry, ca. 1908; AMsS, 49 p.
    [Includes article printed in
    , 7 p. with illustrations by Reginald Birch; includes letter written February 20, 1913 in which John J. Dacey of Marvin, Hooker, Roosevelt, New York discusses the authenticity of "
    Strictly Business
    , " "
    Nashville
    Thimble Thumble
    , " and "
    A Municipal Report
    " with George D. Smith as part of bankruptcy proceedings involving New Hampton Publishing Co.] (Bound in burgundy leather)
  - " The Friendly Call " by O. Henry, ca. 1910; AMsS, 32 p. (Bound in red leather in red cloth slipcase)
    [Includes editorial markings, photograph of O. Henry and article as printed in
    Rolling Stones
    , 15 p.; published in "Monthly Magazine Section," July, 1910.]
- Letters
  - O. Henry to "Mysterious 'A Woman' " [ Ethel Lloyd Patterson], 1905 Sep 17; AL, 7 p.
    [Responds to her answer to a personal he placed in
    The New York Herald
    discusses his search for "congenial company" for himself and a friend; mentions Texas and New York; includes " O. Henry and Me" by Ethel Lloyd Patterson with illustrations by William Oberhardt as printed in
    Everybody's Magazine
    , 6 p.; includes a photograph of O. Henry. ] (Bound in dark blue leather)
  - O. Henry, Battery Park Hotel, Asheville, North Carolina, to [William Aspenwall Bradley], [ca. 1907] Nov 10; ALS, 3 p. w/transcript, 2 p.
    [Discusses insomnia causing him to visit Asheville; mentions expected completion of a "Yucatan story"; Miss Tracy.] (Bound in blue leather with following three letters and a photograph of O. Henry.)
  - O. Henry, Asheville, North Carolina, to [ William Aspenwall Bradley], 1907 Nov 18; ALS, 4 p. w/transcript, 3 p.
    [Discusses his upcoming [marriage], his health, expected completion of a story, plans to return to New York, the possibility of a novel, being "mixed up in the McC[lure] books," and an advance; mentions Sara Lindsay Coleman, Mrs. [William Aspenwall] Bradley, Asheville. ] (Bound in blue leather)
  - O. Henry, The Caledonia, New York to [ William Aspenwall Bradley], [ca. 1908] Oct 21; ALS, 4 p. w/transcript, 1 p.
    [Discusses a change in housing place; mentions Good Ground, [ Long Island].] (Bound in blue leather)
  - O. Henry, The Caledonia, to [William Aspenwall] Bradley, Monday; ALS, 2 p. w/transcript, 1 p
    [Discusses an advance on a story, a story for William Henry Irwin. ].(Bound in blue leather)
  - O. Henry to [William Aspenwall] Bradley, Saturday; ALS, 2 p. w/transcript, 2 p.
    [Discusses illness, getting together with Bradley, taking a friend to see some publishers, a syndicate story, the need to get away, the proofs of some stories, a check.] (Bound in blue leather)